我知道怎么关闭地狱之门了
I figured out how to close the gates of hell.
总体来说  上帝建立了一系列测试
Basically, God built a series of tests,
等你都完成了  就可以去关门了
and when you've done all three, you can slam the gates.
-你需要人帮忙  -我要你安安全全的  萨姆
- You need backup. - No, I need you safe, Sam.
我们都知道结局怎样  我们其中一个要牺牲
We both know where this ends...one of us dies...
我要去做这些测试
I'm gonna do these trials.
我要自己去做  就这样
I'm gonna do them alone -- end of story.
迪恩  你念咒语肯定没用的
The spell's not gonna work for you, Dean.
萨姆  我没能通过测试
Sam, I didn't pass the test.
但是我通过了  剩下的都让我来
But I did...and I'm doing the rest of them.
萨姆
Sam...
我很好  没事
I'm good. I'm okay.
我能行
I can do this.
如今
进入大瀑布
天呐
Oh, god.
不
Oh, no.
见鬼
Dang it.
调度中心  我是7M4  听见了吗
Dispatch, seven-mary-four -- you got your ears on?
请讲7M4
Go ahead, Seven-Mary-Four.
89号公路有肇事逃逸
I got a hit and run on 89.
他死了
He's dead.
尸体状况如何
What's the condition of the body?
看起来冻僵了  请求建议
Looks like he's frozen solid. Please advise.
7M4请原地待命
Seven-Mary-Four, please hold your position.
我们会派救护车前往你的方位
We'll send an ambulance to your location.
怎么回事
What the hell...
凶鬼恶灵
第八季 第十六集
还记得泰坦吗
你是怎么了
What's up with you?
没事  怎么了
Nothing. Why?
凯文有消息吗
Heard from Kevin?
没有
Uh, no. Nothing yet.
这都三周了吧
What's it been, like, three weeks?
小天才怎么拖了这么久
What's taking that little brainiac so long?
就是本书嘛  读就好了
It's a book. Read it.
我胡乱猜的  但是翻译上古文字
Just a guess, but translating an ancient language
又毫无辅助  恐怕比我们想的难
with zero help might be more difficult than we think.
小卡没消息
So, no word from Cass,
凯文也在慢慢来
Kevin's taking his sweet little time,
你又小心翼翼的
and you're acting cagey.
再不来点什么我就要上墙了
We need a lead before I start climbing these walls.
那么
Well, um...
如果是这样  这儿有个僵尸
in that case, I can give you zombies.
肇事逃逸  死在路上  躺了一夜
Guy gets hit by a car, left for dead overnight,
撒了一地肠子肚子
guts spilled out all over the road,
然后起身离开了
then gets up and walks away from it.
没有吃脑子的事吗
Nothing about brain munching?
还记得鲍比的妻子吗
Remember Bobby's wife?
她就没吃脑子
She didn't... munch on any brains.
证人是谁
Well, who's the witness?
蒙大纳州警  20年老警察
Montana state trooper, 20-year vet.
检查了脉搏
Checked his pulse,
看到他内脏撒了一地
saw his insides spilled out all over the place,
然后宣布他已经死亡
pronounced him dead with a capital "D."
蒙大纳州警  大瀑布警局
联调局怎么还追踪起僵尸了
Since when have the Feds started tracking zombie activity?
我们不追踪僵尸
We don't track zombie activity
因为这世上没有僵尸
because there's no such thing as zombies.
跟我们说说你都看到了什么
Why don't you just tell us what you saw?
报纸上都说了
Article said it all --
死挺了  内脏撒了一地  脸冻僵了
Dead as dog poop, guts pecked out, face frozen.
谁能站起来就消失
People don't walk away from that.
只有僵尸
Zombies do.
你不觉得他可能是被什么东西拖走了
And you don't think something could have dragged him away?
只有一组脚印  没有拖动痕迹
One set of footprints, no drag marks.
-你没去追他  -那儿有熊啊
- You didn't go after him? - That's grizzly country.
你给我再多钱我都不会进树林
You couldn't pay me enough to hike those woods,
给我个火箭炮差不多
not without a bazooka.
杰克
Uh, Jack?
我有发现
I got something here.
利文斯顿那边的消息
Came across the wire from Livingston.
无名氏  疑被灰熊打死
John Doe -- presumably mauled by a grizzly.
验尸报告
天呐  就是他
Holy crap, that's him.
-那个死人吗  -死个球啊
- That's the dead guy? - Dead my ass.
那是个僵尸
That's a zombie, boys.
警官先生
Uh, you know what, trooper?
你留在这儿吧
Why don't you stay here?
我们去处理这事
We'll take care of this one.
得有人在这儿留守
We need someone to hold down the fort.
你确定吗
You sure?
如果真遇上《活死人黎明》[著名僵尸电影]了
Yeah, and if things go all "Dawn of the dead" On us,
我们肯定先找你
You'll be our first call.
伙计们
Boys...
爆头[影视作品里杀僵尸的办法]
Aim for the head.
没有身份证明吗
No I.D. on this guy?
指纹也查不到
Fingerprints came up blank, too.
蒙大纳  利文斯顿
这是怎么回事
What's going on down here?
肝脏被吃掉了
Liver was eaten.
我猜是成了鸟食了
Best guess is a bird got at it.
我得承认  我有点失望
I got to say, I am a little disappointed.
是啊  因为你想杀僵尸来着
Yeah, 'cause you wanted to shoot zombies.
我当然想杀僵尸了
Damn straight I wanted to shoot some zombies.
这事再明白不过了
Look, man, this is about as open-and-shut as it gets, all right?
这家伙被车撞死  躺下睡了一觉  醒来
Guy gets mack-trucked, goes down for a nap, wakes up,
绕了一圈进熊窝了  就这么简单
takes a detour into mama bear's den -- end of story.
那他为什么要逃
Then why would he run?
他受伤了
He was injured.
那个警察本会帮他的
That trooper could have helped him.
不知道  有案底
I don't know. Shady past?
迪恩  有案底的人
Dean, don't guys with a shady past
怎么指纹查不到东西啊
usually have a fingerprint on file?
不过他是什么  现在已经死了
Whatever it was, the guy's dead now, all right?
还记得鲍比的话吗
Remember what Bobby said, hmm?
碎木机什么都能干掉
"Wood chipper beats everything"?
灰熊也是
Yeah, well, so does grizzly bear.
你赶快给我交待
You better start talking.
你是什么东西
What are you?
你要是说僵尸  我发誓
If you say, "Zombie," I swear --
什么  不  我什么都不是
What?! No, I'm not anything.
两分钟前  你是具室温的尸体
Look, two minutes ago, you were room temperature.
你肯定有蹊跷
You're something.
我也不知道我怎么回事
Look, I don't know what I am, okay?
我不知道自己是谁
I don't know who I am.
我只知道我总是死掉
All I know is all I do is die,
你要想打死我  请便吧
so if you want to shoot me, shoot me.
但是保证我你能做好
Just promise me you finish the job,
我真是受不了了
'cause I can't take this anymore.
好吧  起来  站起来
All right. Get up, get up, get up. Stand up!
你总是死掉
All you do is die?
这话什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我有记忆以来  每天都死一次
Once a day, for as long as I can remember.
几小时后  我又活过来了
After a few hours, I'm back.
你是活人版肯尼吗
What are you, like a real-life Kenny?
动画片《南方公园》中的角色  总是死掉然后再下一集重生
谁
Who?
不  我叫肖恩
No, my name is Shane.
好吧  听着  肖恩
All right, well, listen, Shane.
我们不能在这儿查明你的身份
We're not gonna find out what the hell you are in here,
你得跟我们走
so you're gonna come with us, okay?
我们会做些测试
We're gonna run a few tests,
确保你没什么问题
Make sure everything's kosher.
测试
Tests?
不是吧
Seriously?
联调局允许你们这么干
This is FBI-sanctioned?
喝下去
Drink.
好吧  那么
All right, so, uh,
你这么长生不死有多久了
how long has this dying thing been going on?
有记忆以来一直如此
As long as I can remember,
但是我只记得几年内的事
but my memory only goes back a few years.
你还有失忆症了
Wait, so now you have amnesia?
你怎么知道自己的名字
How do you know your name?
我真名不叫肖恩
My real name isn't Shane.
这名字是...
It was given to me because...
不知道  我总得有个名字啊
I don't know, people had to call me something.
好吧  那你是怎么回事
Okay. So, then, what happened to you?
我在欧洲一座山上获救
Got pulled off a mountain in Europe.
说是我遇到了一场雪崩
They said that I got caught in an avalanche.
获救之前的事我都不记得了
I don't remember anything from before the rescue.
当我意识到自己的状况
When I realized my condition,
我知道我不能跟人接触
I knew I couldn't be around other people,
所以我造了栋小木屋  学习打猎  自己隐居
so I built a little cabin, learned to hunt, kept to myself.
觉得这样好些
Seemed easiest that way.
然后几个种大麻的
Then a couple pot growers
因为我离他们的大麻田太近而不安
grew nervous with me being so near their crop.
于是打死我两次
Shot me -- twice.
我就觉得我该换个地方了
I figured it was time to move on.
就跑到车轮子底下了
Right into the grille of that pickup.
我能洗洗澡吗
You think maybe I could clean up?
好啊  请便吧
Yeah, man. Knock yourself out.
他绝对有问题
Well, he's definitely something.
是  但或许他并不坏
Yeah, but maybe he's not the monster.
而是个受害者
Maybe he's the victim.
你觉得是诅咒吗
You thinking curse?
可能是巫师干的
Could be looking for a witch, yeah.
这样吧
You know what?
他留在这儿很安全
He's parked here. He's safe.
或许我们该再开间房查个明白
Maybe we should just get another room until we can figure this out.
好吧  但你去给他做腔肠检查找魔法袋
All right, but you're the one going full-cavity for the hex bag.
你是谁
Who are you?
你不记得了吗
You don't remember.
算了
Never mind.
你是谁
Who are you?
我现在是你最可怕的敌人
Now I'm your worst enemy.
那是谁
Who the hell was that?
她说她认识我
She -- she said that she knew me.
怎么个认识法
Yeah, how?
不知道  但她知道我不认识她
I don't know, but, uh, I could have sworn that she was upset
貌似很生气
I didn't know her back.
这可不止是诅咒那么简单
This is, uh -- this is a lot more than a curse, man.
你可挺厉害的啊
You've got, like, some tiger blood.
你在哪学的功夫
Where did you learn that kung fu?
伙计  你没事吧
Hey, buddy, you okay?
没事
Yeah.
我得缓缓
Yeah, I just need a minute.
我这辈子没打过架呢
I've never been in a fight in my whole life.
伙计
Whoa, hey, hey, pal.
你...
Hey. Are you --
他这是心脏病发了吗
Is he having a heart attack?
我们报警吗
Do we call 911?
我们怎么说
And tell them what?
我们从停尸间偷来的死人
That the dead guy we stole from the morgue
活过来犯心脏病了
is alive and having a coronary?
我觉得自己像在服丧
I feel like I'm sitting shiva.
那不是...算了
Well, that's not -- never mind.
我们得想想
Um...we need to think.
迪恩  有什么东西身手堪比杰森・伯恩
Dean, what do we know of that has Jason Bourne fighting skills,
成天死掉  还跟暴力女有段渊源
dies a lot, and has a history with violent women?
不知道  你吗
I don't know -- you?
有事吗
May I help you?
鲍汉姆特工吗
Agent Bonham?
你是
And you are?
这听起来会很怪
This is gonna sound really strange,
但是我在找一具昨天失踪的尸体
But I'm looking for a corpse that went missing today.
验尸官说你们是最后见到他的
The coroner said that you were the last one to see it.
我是海莉
I'm Hayley.
这位是琼斯特工
Uh, this is agent Jones.
你为什么要找无名氏
Why are you looking for our John Doe?
他叫肖恩
Well, his name is Shane.
至少我这么喊他
At least, that's what I called him.
我是他孩子的妈妈
I'm the mother of his son.
跟我拍个手啊
Why don't you, uh, slap me some skin, huh?
他很害羞
He's shy.
没事的  奥利弗
It's okay, Oliver.
你不该看到
Oh, you weren't supposed to see --
没事的
It's okay.
跟这些好联调局特工待着  奥利弗
Stay with the nice FBI agents, Oliver.
我年轻的时候
When I was younger,
我有些朋友想去欧洲爬一座山
I had friends that wanted to climb this mountain in Europe,
我觉得挺好玩的
and I thought it sounded exciting,
就一起去了
so...I joined them.
雪崩吗
The avalanche?
他告诉你们了
He -- he told you?
他还说什么了
What else did he say?
只说他不记得自己怎么去的了
Just that he doesn't remember how he got there.
我朋友都没影了  我找到他时
My friends were gone, and when I found him,
他的衣服撕坏了  眼睛冻僵了
his clothes were torn off, his eyes were frozen solid,
但他还活着
but he was still alive.
我就知道他有什么不对劲的地方
I just knew there was something off about him,
他会...
the way that...he would --
每天都死吗
Die every day?
是啊
Yeah.
我以为他是休克了
I thought it was from exposure or shock.
昏迷不醒
Maybe he was unconscious.
我们当时状况都很差
We were both in bad shape.
如果不是他
And I know I couldn't have made it
我自己肯定不能走下山
down the mountain if it weren't for him.
等我们走到山下时  我们...
And when we got to the bottom, we, um...
意识到我们的感情已经有了变化
realized that it had become something else,
我们就在一起过了一夜
and we spent the night together,
我们在一起的时候  他突然心脏病发
and while we were, you know... he had a heart attack.
尴尬啊
Awkward.
所以我报了警  他们不能救活他
So, I called 911, and they couldn't save him.
我只好去认尸
And I had to go down to I.D. The body...
他却又坐起来了
He popped up again.
活过来了
Alive.
我吓坏了  跑掉了
I freaked out. And I ran.
九个月后我生下了奥利弗
And nine months later, I had Oliver.
我雇了个私家侦探
I hired a private investigator.
我真的努力找他
I really tried to find him,
但是他们放弃后  我也放弃了
but when they gave up, I gave up.
直到几个月前
Until a couple of months ago.
你为什么又开始找了
Now, what made you look again?
最可怕的事
The worst thing.
海莉
Hayley?
你好啊  肖恩
Hello, Shane.
奥利弗  过来
Oliver, come here, honey.
我觉得你们该见面了
I thought it was time you two meet.
这是奥利弗
This is Oliver.
有发现吗
Did you find anything?
嗯
Well, uh...
貌似诅咒的事被我们说中了
Looks like we were right about that curse thing.
一切证据表明  他是个泰坦
From what I can tell, we're looking at a titan.
泰坦  那是神o吗
A titan? What is that -- like, a god?
应该说是神的原型机
More like a proto-god,
神之前的神
like the gods before the gods.
他们曾统治希腊
They ruled over Greece
但后来被宙斯和其他奥利匹亚神推翻了
before Zeus and the rest of the Olympian gods overthrew them.
那这家伙是谁
Okay, so who is this guy?
依我推测
Best I can tell?
他是普罗米修斯
Prometheus.
-不是吧  -是的
- Seriously? - Yeah.
他不是偷了圣火还是什么的
Well, didn't he -- he steal fire or something?
是啊
Yep.
他跑去奥林匹斯山上玩《十一罗汉》
He, uh, "ocean's eleven'd" mount Olympus
并盗走了奥林匹亚之火
and stole the flames of Olympia.
为了找刺激吗
For what, kicks?
实际上是为了我们
For us, actually.
宙斯剥夺了人类造火的能力
Zeus decided to revoke humanity's ability to make fire
我们无法烧饭  无法取暖
so we couldn't cook, couldn't stay warm,
无法照明
couldn't see in the dark.
听起来很糟糕啊
Sounds like a monster's paradise.
这家伙帮了我们吗
And this guy made it right for us?
是的
Yeah.
因为这个
And in return,
宙斯把他绑在那座山上
Zeus decided to strap him to that mountain
让他每天都死一次
and make him relive death every day.
天呐  每天这样过了多久
Damn. Every day for how long?
难怪他疯掉了呢
No wonder the guy's hard drive is fried.
你查到扮成战神西娜的是谁了吗
Did you figure out who, uh, Xena-wannabe was?
我猜是阿耳特弥斯  宙斯的女儿
I'm guessing Artemis, Zeus' daughter.
她携带那把匕首那样的武器
She's been known to carry around weapons like that dagger.
那东西很厉害  能杀死不死之身
They're nasty. They'll kill immortals dead.
好吧
All right.
我们还没对付过神的诅咒呢
Well, we've never battled a god curse before.
希望能打破它
Hope we can break it.
这是一只鹰在啃食你的内脏
This is an eagle chowing down on your intestines.
你不记得吗
You don't remember that?
不
No.
我真不想告诉你
Okay, look, I hate to break it to you,
但你是普罗米修斯
but you are Prometheus.
那我最好
Well, then, the best thing for me
尽量远离他们
is to get as far away from them as I can.
等等  抱歉
Wait. I'm sorry.
你刚发现自己有个七岁大的儿子
You just discovered that you have a seven-year-old son,
你第一反应是跑路吗
And you want to walk away?
我还是个神
And I'm a god.
这个神和他女儿在找我
And this god and his daughter are hunting me.
我有活路吗
What chance do I have?
好吧
Okay.
我们会帮你
We're gonna help you,
但我们得制定个计划
but we need a plan first,
我们在这儿是想不出的
and we can't come up with one here.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
去个安全的地方
Someplace safe.
怎么了
What's wrong?
他摔倒了
He fell.
要我叫救护车吗
Do I need to call an ambulance?
不要
No. Don't.
他要死了  是吗
He's dying, isn't he?
我打算告诉你的
I was going to tell you,
我想给你点时间接受
I just wanted you to have a chance to adjust.
等等  他继承了你的诅咒吗
Wait a second -- he has your curse?
什么诅咒
What curse?
堪萨斯  黎巴嫩
把他放在这儿
Just put him right here.
诅咒是针对你的  他怎么也有
This curse was put on you. Why the kid?
我不知道
I don't know.
你们在说什么诅咒
You keep saying "Curse." What curse?
这种事有多久了
How long has this been happening?
几个月前他满七岁时开始的
Oh, well, I -- since he turned seven a few months ago.
他先是不停死去  然后还不说话了
It started with the dying, and then he stopped talking.
七岁吗
Wait, seven?
七岁是希腊第一次成年的标志
Age seven marks one of the first Greek rites of manhood.
怎么  这个诅咒成了内置程序了吗
So, what? Are you saying the curse is hardwired into his programming?
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
看着我
Look at me.
很抱歉我当年撇下了你
I'm sorry that I ran out on you all those years ago.
我吓坏了
I was scared.
我不明白是怎么回事
I didn't understand what was going on.
但这是我们的孩子
But we have a child,
不管你有什么  他遗传到了
and whatever you have, he has.
我得知道怎么阻止
I need to know how to stop it.
是什么诅咒
What curse?
奥利的爸爸是个希腊神
Okay, so Ollie's dad is a Greek God
宙斯诅咒他每天都要死一次
who has been cursed to die every day by Zeus.
你们俩是驱鬼人
And you guys are...ghostbusters.
我听错了吗
Am I getting this right?
鉴于你儿子
Well, you know, due to the fact that your son
目前  尽管只是暂时  死了
is currently, albeit temporarily, dead,
我就不跟你计较了
I'm gonna let that one slide.
这一切太疯狂了
You have to realize this sounds crazy.
是真的
It's true.
我一开始也不信
I didn't believe it myself at first,
但只有这样才说得通
but it's the only thing that makes sense.
你早点接受这一切
Look, the faster you wrap your brain around this,
我们就能早点解决问题
the faster we can solve the problem.
解决问题
Solve the problem?
我都不知道我有没有理解问题
I-I'm just not even sure I understand the problem.
好吧
All right.
通常我们的做法是  召唤这混蛋过来
So, the way we usually handle this is we summon the bastard
不断折磨他  直到他撤销诅咒
and we work him over until he undoes whatever it is he did.
召唤宙斯
Summon Zeus.
没错
Yes.
要是他不肯撤销呢
And if he doesn't want to undo it?
那我们就杀了他
Then we take him out.
希望诅咒会随他一起消失
And hopefully, the curse dies along with him.
怎么会发生这种事
This can't be happening.
这个我能处理
This I can handle.
你可以一辈子逃亡  躲避  死掉
Listen, you can run and hide and die for all eternity.
这是你的选择
It's your choice.
但我和萨姆会去找宙斯
But Sam and I are gonna go after Zeus...
你来不来都无所谓
With or without you.
我加入
I'm in.
有了
Here we go.
什么
What you got?
龙的阴茎
Dragon penis.
什么
What?
一个叫龙根的古希腊猎魔人写的
Ancient Greek hunter by the name of Drakopoolos.
就我看来  他是个狠角色
Near as I can tell, he was a badass
顺便一说  他的名字是希腊...
whose name, incidentally, is Greek --
别说了  我来吧
No, no, no. I got that.
谢了  干得好
Thanks, ace.
孩子怎么样了
How's the, uh... is the kid?
没事
He's fine.
请继续
Oh, please, keep going.
很久以前  龙根和宙斯干了一架
Right, so, uh, Drakopoolos tangled with Zeus back in the day,
记录者翻译了他的日记
and the men of letters translated his journal.
记录者
The men of letters?
是个神秘团体
It's a secret society.
这里就是他们的基地
This is actually their lair.
我们是传人
We're legacies.
没什么大不了
No big deal.
好了
Okay.
这里写着  他将宙斯召唤进一个陷阱
So, it says here he summoned Zeus into a trap
找到了杀他的方法
and found out how to kill him.
什么方法
What's that?
被闪电击中的树木
Wood from a tree struck by lightning.
要召唤宙斯需要两件东西
So, it says we need two things for the summon --
宙斯手上冻住的能量
frozen energy from the hand of Zeus,
以及其信徒的尸骨
and the bone of a worshipper.
冻住的能量  是闪电熔岩吗
Frozen energy -- you thinking fulgurite?
很合理
Well, it makes sense.
好吧
All right.
你上网查一下  附近有没有
You get on the web, see if there's any Greeks nearby
还在膜拜上古之神的希腊人
that are still worshipping the Old Gods.
马上查
On it.
那木头呢  容易找吗
W-what about the wood? Is that easy to find?
需要点运气
With a little bit of luck.
等等  日记就这么断了
Wait -- t-this journal just ends.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我们怎么知道那个龙什么的有没有活下来
I mean, how do we know if Drako-whatever survived?
宙斯有没有报复他
How do we know Zeus didn't get to him?
我们不知道
We don't know.
我们怎么知道这方法有用
How do we know this is going to work?
我们从来都不确定  不过这些书
We never know for sure, but these books --
一般都挺靠谱的
They're, uh, they're pretty good.
我们就把命交给一个叫什么阴茎的人
So, we're hanging our lives on the writings of a dead man
写的书吗
who...is named after genitalia.
名字翻得不太准确
It's a loose translation.
真是专家
Experts.
好了  听听这个
All right. Listen to this.
隔两个镇就有希腊异教徒  最棒的是
Greek pagans two towns over. Best part?
他们有个记载墓地的讣告页
They have an obit page with cemeteries.
好吧
All right.
你俩去挖坟墓
You two are on grave duty.
我们来搞定B&E
We'll handle the B&E.
保持联系
We'll be in touch.
B&E  是指私闯民宅吗
B&E? You mean, breaking and entering?
为什么
What for?
书里说我们需要闪电熔岩
Well, the book calls for fulgurite.
挺难弄到的
It's a little hard to come by.
上次要用这东西
The last time we needed it,
我们是从一个富翁那偷的
we, uh, stole it from a one-percenter.
你知道所有卖水晶的店
You do know that fulgurite is available
都有卖闪电熔岩的吧
in crystal shops all over, right?
-是吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
新新人类用闪电熔岩来做廉价首饰
The new age people, they use it to make cheap jewelry.
你为什么这么做  萨姆
Why are you doing this, Sam?
我们需要骨头  所以得挖坟
We need a bone, so I dig.
不  我是说这么帮我们
No, I mean for us.
这不关你的事
This isn't your problem.
你却拿自己的命冒险
You're risking your life.
你为什么拿自己的命冒险盗火
Why'd you risk yours to steal that fire?
问得好
Good question.
可惜我记不得了
Wish I could remember.
相信我  这是值得的
Trust me on this -- it was worth it.
你差不多拯救了全世界
You pretty much, uh, saved the whole world.
是啊
Yeah, I guess.
但如果我不能救我儿子  那一切
But none of that -- none of that means anything
都毫无意义
unless I can save my son.
我知道这一切看起来不太靠谱
Listen, I know this all seems a little haphazard, all right?
但是你相信我  我和萨姆
But trust me when I say that me and Sammy
还有更没把握最终还是致胜的时候呢
have gone in with a lot less and come out on top.
我相信你
I believe you.
只是这一切
It's just all this.
我就要恳求希腊神o宙斯
And I'm about to ask Zeus, the Greek god,
治好我的儿子
to help cure my son.
你得记住
Then you got to remember
我们不是要求他帮忙
is this is not about asking for his help, okay?
他不是你朋友
He's not your friend.
他得做他该做的
It's about getting him to do what's right.
保持冷静
Stay calm.
得了
Oh, come now.
就不能有点礼貌吗
Can't we do this civilized?
这得看你的了
Well, it depends on you.
我们只需要你解除一个孩子身上的诅咒
All we need is to break a curse you put on a little kid.
所以你就痛快答应了  我们好各回各家
So, how about you say, "Yes," and we all go home?
再见到你很高兴  普罗米修斯
Nice to see you again, Prometheus.
都收拾干净了
All cleaned up.
我在到处找你呢
I've been looking for you.
你太过分了  宙斯
It's gone too far, Zeus.
解除诅咒
Break the curse.
是你的儿子受了诅咒
It's your child who has the affliction.
真有意思
Interesting.
你打算怎么做
So, what's it gonna be?
是好好配合  还是我们来硬的
The easy way or we could do this the hard way.
打开陷阱我就打破诅咒
Break the trap, dear man, and I'll break the curse.
没门
No dice.
治好那孩子
Fix the kid.
一次机会
Going once...
别犯傻
Don't be that guy.
两次机会
Going twice...
你烂在这儿我都不在乎
Hey, you can rot here for all I care.
是啊  那孩子就要继续受折磨
Yes, and the child will continue to suffer.
我们走吧
Let's roll.
他需要我  你很清楚
He needs me, and you know it.
不
No!
海莉  别
Hayley, no!
救我的儿子
Now save my son.
现在怎么办
What do you say?
我们来硬的好吗
Shall we try this the hard way?
把孩子带过来
Bring forth the child.
有请了
Please.
该死
Balls.
你们见过我女儿了吧
I trust you've met my daughter.
海莉不要啊
Hayley, don't do it.
这是普罗米修斯的儿子
This is the son of Prometheus.
他受了诅咒  要每天都死去
And he's cursed to suffer death every day.
我得承认  我从没想要这么可爱的孩子
I must admit, I could never have conceived such a horrible fate
遭受这么可怕的命运
for such a beautiful child.
这就证明了
Just goes to show,
总要为可喜的意外做准备
we must all leave room for happy accidents.
你什么意思  我不明白
What does that mean? I don't understand.
告诉我
Tell me,
普罗米修斯看到过孩子死去吗
Has Prometheus experienced the child's death yet?
他什么反应
How did he take it?
他痛苦吗
Did he hurt?
很好
Good.
想象你一千个孩子同时死去
Imagine a thousand children all dying in unison.
那样你才会理解我的痛苦
Only then would you understand my pain.
但人不能总是如愿  所以
But we can't always have what we want, so...
就用这一个将就吧
...one will have to do.
不
No.
我有件特别的任务交给你
I have a special job for you, my little friend.
阿耳特弥斯
Artemis.
走
Move.
你知道现在领我们去赴死的是谁吗  迪恩
So, you know who this is, Dean, walking us to our deaths?
不知道  不在乎
Don't know. Don't care.
是我们的神  阿耳特弥斯  猎神
It's our god, Artemis -- the goddess of hunters.
真有意思啊
Oh, that's fascinating.
我们猎杀蛇发女怪和牛头怪时
See, she's who we'd pray to for courage
就要祈祷她赐我们勇气
when hunting the gorgon or the Minotaur.
不过她现在已经不值得我们崇拜了
Of course, she's not really worship worthy anymore,
因为她已经大不如前了
uh, having lost a step and all.
我才没有
The hell I have.
萨姆  你不是吧  跟神撂狠话
Really, Sam? Trash-talking a god?
有没有搞错啊
Seriously?
看看我们能不能弥补一下
So, let's see if we can make up
这七年的时光
for seven years of lost time.
还像以前一样厉害吗
Still at full power? Really?
那怎么花了七年才找到普罗米修斯
Then why did it take you seven years to track down Prometheus?
他在躲着我
He was hiding.
躲着你
Hiding from you?
猎神居然找不到蒙大纳的小木屋吗
So the god of hunters couldn't find a shack in montana?
或许你根本不想找到他
Maybe it's that you didn't want to find him.
萨姆  你干得漂亮
Good, Sam, you're doing great.
你父亲会杀了那孩子的  你知道吗
Your dad's gonna kill that kid, you know?
别担心
Don't worry.
他会再活过来的
He'll come back.
你就不行了
Unlike you.
他爱上你了  你知道吗
He was in love with you, you know.
他告诉我们了
He told us.
你说谎
You lie.
那好吧
Okay, sure, yeah.
你爱信不信
Believe whatever you want.
不  不
No, no, no, no.
先别昏过去
Don't pass out on me just yet.
我这才刚开始呢
I'm only just getting started.
他对你说了什么
What did he say to you?
那不是他第一次逃离那座山
This wasn't the first time he escaped that mountain.
你答应放他走
And that you let him go free,
条件是他不把约会的事告诉你父亲
as long as you could hide your little tryst from the old man.
他才不会这么说呢
The hell he said.
他大脑一片混乱
His brain is mush.
是吗  那我是怎么知道的
Oh, yeah? Then how did I know?
你告诉过其他人吗
What, have you spilled it to anyone?
荷马  赫西奥德  希罗多德
Homer? Hesiod? Herodotus?
前两位是希腊诗人  后一位是史学家
当然没有
Of course not.
你怕你父亲会发现
You were afraid big daddy would find out
你爱上了这个世界上他最恨的人
that you fell for the person he hates most in this world.
当然了  当他看到那篇僵尸的报道
Of course, when he saw the zombie article,
不论多么心痛
It kind of forced your hand,
你都必须来除掉他
and you had to come hunt him down no matter how much it hurt.
你尽管下手吧
You know what? Go ahead.
杀了我们
Kill us.
让你父亲杀了那个男孩
And let your father slaughter that boy.
一次又一次地杀他
Over and over again.
连疤痕都不会留
That won't leave a mark.
你喜欢永生  对不对
You like being an immortal, don't you?
是啊  你每天都会死
Oh, sure, you die every day,
但是没有东西可以让你一直死去
but nothing can keep you dead.
那就像是打盹一样
It's almost like taking a little nap.
所有的焦心和顾虑会暂时消失一会儿
All of your cares and worries disappear for a little while.
该睡觉了  乖孩子
Well, it's sleepy time, my dear boy.
这必须停下  父亲
This has to stop, father.
停下
Stop?
我才刚刚开始
I'm only just getting started.
你做的够多了
You've done enough.
我是为了我们和其他神o
I am doing this for us...for our kind.
就因为他  我们虽然在世  却无法统治世界
He is the reason we're here and not ruling the world.
就因为他  世人遗忘了我们
He's the reason they have forgotten all about us.
放他们走
Let them go.
放他们都走
All of them.
我是你父亲  你要服从我
I am your father, and you will obey me.
你曾是我的父亲
You were once my father.
现在你只是个陌生人
Now you're someone else.
看着你死去  我从不觉得烦
I never get tired of watching you die.
你的孩子要上山了
Your boy is going on the mountain.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这样吧
You know what?
我们去买一些圣代冰淇淋怎么样
How about we go get some ice-cream sundaes?
不要
No.
我想留下来
I'd like to stay.
敬那捉摸不定的爱情
Well, here's to that crazy little wild card called love.
你怎么知道阿耳特弥斯爱上了普罗米修斯
How did you know Artemis had the hots for Prometheus, anyway?
直觉
Intuition.
或是运气
Uh...luck.
好吧  无论是什么  那还算挺有用
Yeah, well, whatever it was, it worked...pretty much.
至少那孩子没事
At least the kid's all right.
你知道吗
You know...
我开始觉得也许我是天真了
I'm starting to think maybe I was being naive.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我是说认为我自己可以
When I said that I could just will myself
毫发无损地通过那三项测试
into coming out of these trials unscathed.
不  不
No, no, no.
不要这样闷闷不乐  好吗
Stop with the sullen emo crap, all right?
你不会像普罗米修斯那样死去的
That's...you're not gonna die like Prometheus.
你怎么知道  迪恩
How do you know, Dean?
鲍比  鲁弗斯  现在是普罗米修斯
Bobby, Rufus, now Prometheus...
你觉得他们有谁选择了死去吗
You think any of them chose death?
没有
No.
是命运替他们做了选择
The life chose for them.
好吧  但你答应过  好吗
Yeah, well, you promised, okay?
你答应我会过再正常不过的生活
You promised to live a long, Clark Griswold life
还会去做前列腺和结肠镜检查
full of prostate exams and colonoscopies, all right?
你别想食言  我不允许
You're not welshing on that deal, not on my watch.
你就算死  也得是自然死亡
If you die, it's gonna be because of something normal.
比如突发心脏病
Like a heart attack?
没错
Exactly.
快吃汉堡吧
Yeah, eat your burger.
小卡  你在听吗
Cass, you got your ears on?
你知道我不是个爱祈祷的人
Listen, you know I am not one for praying,
因为对我来说  那无异于恳求
'cause in my book it's... it's the same as begging.
但这和萨姆有关  所以你得听着
But this is about Sam, so I need you to hear me.
我们完全不了解情况
We are going into this deal blind.
我不知道会发生什么
And I don't know what's ahead
或者萨姆会遇到什么
or what it's gonna bring for Sam.
他虽然藏得很好
Now, he's covering pretty good,
但我知道他很痛苦
but I know that he is hurting,
而这些本该由我来承受
and this one was supposed to be on me.
所以  看在我们这么多年来的份上
So, for all that we've been through,
我求你
I'm asking you...
照顾一下我弟弟  好吗
...you keep a lookout for my little brother, okay?
你到底在哪  老兄
Where the hell are you, man?